A Guide to the Asia Society photographs and special formats FA105
Rockefeller Archive Center
Asia Society photographs and special formats
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Asia Society
FA105
15 Box(es) Extent is an estimate.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
File Plan
Former Classification: P/1075
Conditions Governing Access
Collection restricted from scholarly research, pending further archival processing.
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Photographs; Kashmir; Japan; Korea; China; Hawaii; Asia Society; Asia Society
- Audiovisual materials, 1
  Arrangement
  Alphabetical.
  Conditions Governing Access
  When requesting to view films -- please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1902).
  If the item does not have a designated AV number, please refer to the Title and the Film Number (which consists of a combination of Roman numerals and alphanumerics - example: III 14.1-6).
  - Tassilo Adam films, bulk; 49 Film Reels Tassilo Adam film collection encompasses approximately 25,000 feet of film on 49 reels. The collection includes 35 negatives and 14 prints in 16mm and 35mm formats.
    Biographical / Historical
    Tassilo Adam (1878-1955) was a German-born ethnographer who was appointed the official Ethnologist of the Dutch East Indies by the Governor General of Java. He was a photographer and amateur filmmaker with an anthropological and documentary approach to the Indonesian culture he captured on film. From 1929-1955, Adam was the curator of Oriental Art at the Brooklyn Museum.
    Scope and Contents
    Tassilo Adam film collection encompasses approximately 25,000 feet of film on 49 reels. The collection includes 35 negatives and 14 prints in 16mm and 35mm formats.
    The documentary footage was shot in Indonesia from 1921-1928 of dances, shadow play, dramatic dance, religious processions, wedding festivals in the palaces, and other ceremonies as well as dance finery, costumes of the Javanese nobles, everyday wear and dance attire. The bulk of the collection is of Central Java, comprising of court ceremonies and dances at the palaces of Jogyakarta and Surakarta, as well as village performances and rituals in the surrounding area.
    Highlights of the collection include the films that capture
    • Wayang Wong, a type of classical Javanese dance theatrical performance with themes taken from episodes of the Ramayana or Mahabharata
    • Wayang Topeng, a Javanese theatrical performance in which performers wear masks.
    • Kuda Kepang or Kuda Lumping, a traditional Javanese dance depicting a group of horsemen.
    • Serimpi, a classical dance of Cental Java associated with royal palaces of Yogyakarta and Surakarta. The dance epitomizes the character of the royal court, and the dance became an important symbol of the ruler’s power as well as the refinement of Javanese culture.
    • Bedoyo dances, is a ritualized dance of Java and is associated with the royal palaces of Yogyakarta and Surakarta. The dance epitomizes the character of the royal court, and the dance became an important symbol of the ruler’s power.
    • Wayang Kulit, a Javanese shadow puppet theatrical performance
    • Gamelan, a traditional orchestra of Java and Bali in Indonesia, made up predominantly of percussive instruments.
    - Tassilo Adam film I, Silent, Black and white, 28 minutes. Available on 16mm film. Condition is okay. There is a slight odor and film stock alters between single and double perforation.; 16mm acetate film base, 1005 feet. (Reel AV 2335)
      All inquires to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
      Scenes of male/female couple dancing with a band in the background, male/female dancers modeling their costume and head gear. Includes Reel 8 (Java). Procession of community bringing gifts, soldiers at shooting practice, intertitles about children as little soldiers, footage of the Susuhunan, archers, the golden throne. Includes "Painter Speis". Footage of animal costume, parachute/hot air balloon, people bringing statues to the mountain, crowd carrying cone shaped monuments down the street. Includes "Court DJO-VG Karta". Includes scenes of elders modeling wardrobes and hats, albino villager. Intertitles about the Sultan's officials, Eldest Pangeran, Assistant Resident, His Highness the Sultan of Jogjakarta, Hamangku Buwono III, Gooningans (gifts).
      File Plan
      IV 3B Fe 1
    - Kraton Surakarta Dan Sekitarnya, Silent, Black and white, 23 minutes. Available on 16mm format. Condition is okay. Film smells of vinegar syndrome.; 16mm acetate film base, 853 feet. (Reel AV 2334)
      Includes footage of hand motions and dancing, possible theatrical storytelling related to battles and fighting, footage of procession as extravogent carriage arrives, temple on a mountain, soldiers in shooting practice, community meeting presenting gifts to a leader, wayang shadow puppet show, gamelon orchestra accompanys wayang performance, young women posing and laughing in front of the camera, and additional footage of women dancing and rehearsing.
      IV 3B6 Fe 3
    - Sugar Plantation I, Silent, Black and white, 7 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 263 feet. (Reel AV 2290)
      Scenes of plantation workers' housing, fields, workers, plantation houses, Ford Model T driving on roadways, village (company town), school children, church, hospital, doctor at work, operation room, island road, view of mountains, river and waterfall.
      IV 3B6 Fe 4
    - Sugar Plantation II, Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm film. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 376 feet. (Reel AV 2291)
      Scenes of people working in the sugar cane fields, transportation of sugar cane on trains and ox carts, processing sugar cane for shipment, loading on frieghts, warehouse and plantation houses, industrial machinery processing sugar cane in a refinery.
    - Dancing XI (NIAS MAKE PRINT), Silent, Black and white, 21 minutes. Available on 16mm film. Condition is okay. Film smells of vinegar syndrome.; 16mm acetate film base, 781 feet. (Reel AV 2306)
      Footage of warriors in traditional costume dress. Children excerising by jumping over walls and dancing to gongs. Includes scenes of warrior dance, chiefs, ironmongs, making cloth, bathing a baby, female making flour, kids playing a ballgame, chief and warriors assembled, kids going to school, carrying water, four men making flour, cutting coconuts, greeting people, man getting lip cut, warriors marching and dancing, showing fighting technique, village assembly and butchering.
      IV 3B6 Fe 2
    - Kraton Yogyakarta Dan Sekitarnya, Silent, Black and white, 38 minutes. Available on 16mm film. Condition is okay. Film has many splices.; 16mm acetate film base, 1402 feet. (Reel AV 2336)
      Scenes of dignitaries saying goodbye then driving off, village buildings and surroundings, communal cooking practices, woodworking, metalworking, village manufacturing, bowlmaking. Villagers show off their handiwork, parade procession, seaside, villagers take posessions out to the water, villagers showing interest and curiosity about the camera, dancers display head dress, musicans playing. Community gathers to see variety of performances by adults and children. Footage of animal costumes, performers showing off faces and makeup, child performers, children swimmining in a pool, young men as scouts being watched by a crowd, parachute/hot air balloon, outfits of soldiers, crowd carrying pyramids with military fanfare.
      IV 3B6 Ff 1
    - Reel 8, Silent, Black and white, 5 minutes. Available on 16mm film. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 196 feet. (Reel AV 2307)
      Footage of temples, statues, scupltures, reliefs and relics. Scene of excavators in temple. Temple dedicated to Brahma and Temple of Shiva are featured in the footage.
      IV 3B6 Ff 2
    - Java Street Scene XIII, Silent, Black and white, 5 minutes. Available on 16mm film. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 207 feet. (Reel AV 2308)
      Street scenes of Java featuring people walking and holding flags.
    - Clowns Love Dance, Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 319 feet. (Reel AV 2309)
      Scenes of gamelan orchestra, male costumed dancers performing, drawves dancing, people dancing in various costumes- skeletons, birds, dragons, boar, snake, oxen, elephant, deer and panther.
    - Solo Sultan, Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 358 feet. (Reel AV 2310)
      Scenes of young girls, horse drawn carriages, royal processions, men doing military manuevers with rifles, canons bring fired and marching band.
    - Sultan's Court, Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm film. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film, black and white negative, 384 feet. (Reel AV 2311)
      Scenes of dancing, musicans, people getting in and out of cars and royal procession.
    - Dancer Court, Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 387 feet. (Reel AV 2326)
      Scenes of female dancers dancing, and displaying and modeling costumes for the camera. Male dancers stick fighting, dancing with lancings and play fighting.
      IV 3B6 Ff 3
    - Pram Banan, Silent, Black and white, 7 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 276 feet. (Reel AV 2327)
      Scenes of markets, temples, temple statues, scultural relief, warriors dancing and stick fighting.
    - Celebes VII, Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 408 feet. (Reel AV 2328)
      Scenes of map showing trip and stops, Welcome arch, people lined up waving, warrior dances, parade, island views, waterfall, harbor, passenger liner at the dock, "mansion", old fort, temple, speed boat, shoreline, cliffs, ceremonial dance, village market.
    - Ballon Bedoyos, Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes. Available on 16mm. Conditin is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 331 feet. (Reel AV 2329)
      Scenes of a group of female court dancers and gamelon orchestra.
    - Hunter Speis, Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 329 feet. (Reel AV 2330)
      Scenes of outdoor footage, temples, clowns, mountain tops, costumed people in masks sitting.
    - NIAS, Silent, Black and white, 12 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 455 feet. (Reel AV 2331)
      Scenes of people in costumes, warriors with weapons exercising, children dancing to gongs, warrior dance, chiefs, ironmongs, making cloth, bathing a baby, female making flous, kids playing a ballgame, chief and warriors assembled, kids going to school, carrying water, four men making flour, cutting coconuts, greeting people, man getting lip cut, warriors marching and dancing, showing fighting techniques, village assembly and butchering.
    - JAVA 1000 - 11, Silent, Black and white, 4 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 160 feet. (Reel AV 2312)
      Scenes of creating and working with bronzeware and pottery. Final products (gong, plate, bowls, lamp) are displayed.
      IV 3B6 Ff 5
    - Java 5, Silent, Black and white, 7 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 285 feet. (Reel AV 2313)
      Scenes of dancing.
    - Madura, Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 326 feet. (Reel AV 2314)
      Footage of Madura Island off the Northeast coast of Java in Indonesia. Scenes of people getting in and out of cars, bronzeworking, weaving, street scenes, temple scuplture relief.
    - Can G22N, Silent, Black and white, 16 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 578 feet. (Reel AV 2315)
      Scenes of people getting in and out of cars, bull racing, children cwimming, fabric working.
    - Java # 2, Silent, Black and white, 7 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 276 feet. (Reel AV 2316)
      Scenes of military manuevers with rifles, bronze and woodworking.
    - Court DJO-VG Karta, Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 368 feet. (Reel AV 2317)
      Scenes of the sultan with intertitle cards describing actions. Intertitle cards "His Highness the Sultan of Jogjakarta, Hamangku Buwono VIIL (Hamengkubuwono VIII ?)", "The Gooningana (gifts) are carried to the mosque to be blessed.", "The regenis and the High Council or their way to the Mosque."
    - Java Reel 5, Silent, Black and white, 26 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 960 feet. (Reel AV 2332)
      Includes Java Reel 5-8. Footage of landscapes, hiking through the mountains, warriors holding lances, person in traditional dress displaying self for camera, processions, soldiers marching, practicing dancing, markets and trading with women. Women in traditional dress trading, washing fabric, dancing with an assembly of instruments, modeling traditional dance amd fashion, parade of people bearing gifts/treasures and rifle practice. Intertitle in Dutch "Americans on the Road to Surabaya for celebration."
      IV 3B6 Fg 1
    - Java Reel 1, Silent, Black and white, 35 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 1263 feet. (Reel AV 2333)
      Includes Java Reel 1-4. Includes Dutch intertitles. Footage of female dancers, sports activities such as chariot racing, guests arriving at a party, agriculutural practices, craftmanship, metalworking, volcano, two villagers showing off personal items. Dolls on mountain tops watching over the spirits of human sacrifices, community at beach playing in water, processions, limestone cliffs, marching soldiers. Footage off shore in a commerical boat, footage of Pieter Corneliszoon Hooft steamship with passagers waiting to board, a woman showing off her baby in a wrap on the dock, and view of the coast and shipping years.
    - Count Sola, Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 387 feet. (Reel AV 2318)
      Scenes of royal procession, military troop manuevers with rifles, gamelan performance, wayang performance, dancers performing outside and warrior dance.
    - Soldiers Court Hair Ceremony R-11, Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 373 feet. (Reel AV 2319)
      IV 3B6 Fg 2
      Scenes of military procession.
    - Horse Dance, Silent, Black and white, 18 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 655 feet. (Reel AV 2320)
      Scenes of kuda lumping (horse dance) and slaying a dragon. Dancers "riding" on horses made from woen bammboo and decorated with colorful paints and cloth.
    - Court of Solo, Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 290 feet. (Reel AV 2321)
      Scenes with intertitles. Intertitles read - "The archers of the body guard of the Susuhunan.", "Bearers of the holy weapons, golden ornaments etc. of past ages.", "The golden throne of the Susuhunan.", "The Susuhunan (Emperor) of Surakarta with the resident." Scenes of military troop manuevers with rifles.
    - Wong Dancers, Silent, Black and white, 6 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 248 feet. (Reel AV 2322)
      Scenes of Wayang wong dancers, a classical Javanese dance theaterical performance.
    - Bodayo Solo, Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 355 feet. (Reel AV 2323)
      Scenes of gamelan orchestra, people in animal costumes, group of female court dancers.
    - Funeral, Silent, Black and white, 6 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 226 feet. (Reel AV 2324)
      Scenes of the funeral of the sultan, funerary procession, crowds of people walking and carrying the coffin of the sultan, horse drawn carriages, people climbing up and down stairs.
    - Repeat Love Dance, Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 340 feet. (Reel AV 2325)
      Scenes of gamelan orchestra, horse dance, performers in masks, creating puppets for shadow puppet theater performance, shadow puppet theater performed.
    - Java Reel, Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes. Available on 35mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, 762 feet. (Reel AV 2300)
      Scenes of dancers showing the choreography, examples of dancers' head dress, competition with oxen. Includes Dutch intertitles.
      IV 3B6 f 18
    - Java Reel 3, Silent, Black and white, 7 minutes. Available on 35mm. Condition is good, slight odor.; 35mm acetate film base, black and white negative/positive/fine grain, 671 feet. (Reel AV 2303)
      Includes scenes of a view of Sanitarium Tosari, men smoking cigarettes, a volcano, moving possessions out of a house, slaughtering a goat, mountain statues, a parade, villagers traveling around the mountain and land, and soldiers standing at attention and marching.
      IV 3B6 Fc 3
    - Java Reel 2, Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes. Available on 35mm. Condition is good; slight odor.; Includes scenes of dancers practing choreography, farmers reveal how agriculture is done, picking wheat stalks, farmers cleaning wheat in the water, attaching an ox to a cart. Footage of farmland, bowl manufactures, sign reads "Kunstarbeid djokja", example of worthy posessions.; 35mm acetate film base, black and white positive/fine grain, 805 feet. (Reel AV 2301)
      IV 3B6 Fc 2
    - Java Reel 4, Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes. Available on 35mm. Condition is good; slight odor.; 35mm acetate film base, black and white positive/fine grain, 671 feet. (Reel AV 2302)
      Footage of sailboats from a ship at sea, docks and the shore, passengers stepping off of the boat Pieter Corneliszoon Hooft, long shot of city from view of ship. Footage of what the boat passes on its trip, examples of smaller modes of transportation inside the city, view of the land from the boat.
    - Java Reel 5 and 6, Silent, Black and white, 7 minutes. Available on 35mm. Condition is good/slight odor.; 35mm acetate film base, black and white positive/fine grain, 637 feet. (Reel AV 2299)
      Footage of a train, basin and mountains, volcano, landscape scenery shots, view of the Sanitorium (outside only).
      IV 3B6 f 22
    - Java Reel 6 Part 5082 to end, Silent, Black and white, 6 minutes. Available on 35mm. Condition is good; slight odor.; 35mm acetate film base, black and white positive/fine grain, 544 feet. (Reel AV 2298)
      Includes scenes of men carrying pyramid structures (tomb or coffin?), man showing fine fabrics or clothing, procession with gifts and soldiers entering with spears.
      IV 3B6 f 23
    - Java Reel 7, Silent, Black and white, 7 minutes. Available on 35mm. Condition is good.; 35mm acetate film base, black and white positive/fine grain, 685 feet. (Reel AV 2297)
      Includes scenes of two men dancing, a female dancer, a village market and the making and selling of food. Footage of fabric working, laundring, dying and retouching, 2 dancers and the band that provides their music. Includes Dutch intertitles.
      IV 3B6 f 24
    - Java Reel 10, Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes. Available on 35mm. Condition is good.; 35mm acetate film base, black and white positive/fine grain, 724 feet. (Reel AV 2296)
      Footage includes Dutch intertitles. Scenes of a state coach transport being lead by soldiers, a train bringing the coffin to the Imogiri (a royal grave complex in Yogyakarta in south-central Java), footage of massive stair paths, young females acknowledging the camera, male dancers with sticks, puppetry making, gamelan orchestra playing, and a wayang puppetry performance.
      IV 3B6 f 27
    - Java Reel 11, Silent, Black and white, 7 minutes. Available on 35mm. Condition is good.; 35mm acetate film base, black and white positive/fine grain, 701 feet. (Reel AV 2295)
      Footage of marketplace selling hats, baskets, food, communal cooking, crowd with flags, women and men carrying gifts under rain cover. Includes Dutch intertitles.
      IV 3B6 f 28
    - Nature Life, Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base black and white white, 409 feet. (Reel AV 2275)
      Scenes of Indonesian landscapes, people climbing mountains, village life, rice farming and village markets.
      IV 3B6 f 30
    - Reel L, Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white megative, 323 feet. (Reel AV 2274)
      Footage of Indonesia wedding ceremony with the Sultan as a guest. Scenes of wedding procession and footage of Wayang, Javanese shadow puppet theater with gamelan orchestra. Dutch and Englishs intertitles.
      IV 3B6 f 32
    - Arts and Crafts, Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 317 feet. (Reel AV 2273)
      Scenes of brass production, weaving and fabric working, wood carving and ceremonial procession with traditional costume, performance and music.
      IV 3B6 f 33
    - Dutch Ship, Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 322 feet. (Reel AV 2272)
      Harbor scenes, small sailing craft, barges, passengers debarking, rickshaws, city scenes. Footage of the Dutch ocean liner Pieter Corneliszoon Hooft.
      IV 3B6 f 34
    - Court Repeats and Village Life, Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 356 feet. (Reel AV 2271)
      Footage of Indonesia cort procession, military drills, traditional costume and important people (military, religious, social) and scenes of rural village life including field work, women crafting, creating and working with fabric, men creating crockery and plowing rice rices with oxen.